Abdullah Solahudeen

Front End Developer

Km 7, Lagos-Ibadan Exp. way, Obantoko, Abeokuta Ogun

(234) 7055997165 solahudeen15@gmail.com

Background

Solution-driven Front End Developer adept at contributing to a highly collaborative work environment, finding solutions and determining customer satisfaction. Proven experience developing consumer-focused websites using HTML, CSS and JavaScript. Built products for desktop and mobile app users over 3+ years, meeting highest standards for web design, user experience, best practices and speed. Designed and developed web applications across multiple APIs, third-party integrations and databases.

Skills

- HTML / CSS
- Javascript (ES6)
- React
- Redux
- Firebase
- Material UI
- Styled Components
- Git
- Bash shell

Experience

HIC Mikrolab / Software Engineer

FEBRUARY 2022 - PRESENT, OGUN

- Work with software development and testing team members to design and develop robust solutions to meet client requirements for functionality, scalability and performance.
- Engaged with clients to plan and optimize site issues and queries.
- Researched emerging web technologies and trends for possible incorporation into sites.
- Designed and updated layouts to meet usability and performance requirements.

PricewaterhouseCoopers Nig. / Advisory Intern

MARCH 2019 - FEBRUARY 2020, LAGOS

- Using business tools such as Salesforce to deliver on dedicated tasks
- Preparing Invoice
- Setting up and moderating BU meetings
- Procuring and maintaining the business unit equipments
- Scheduled conference rooms, prepared agendas and maintained calendars to prepare for meetings and events.
- Supported projects and initiatives to improve service offerings and platform support.
- Supported office manager with proactive correspondence management, document coordination and customer relations.

YEMTECH / Web Developer

JANUARY 2018 - MARCH 2019, LAGOS

- Developed user interfaces with modern JavaScript frameworks, HTML5 and CSS3.
- Enhanced functionality and appearance of websites and repaired functionality issues.
- Lecture students on Computer Desktop Publishing
- Network administration and troubleshooting
- Adapted quickly to a constantly changing, deadline-driven environment.

Education

Federal University of Agriculture, Abeokuta / Bsc. Computer Science

NOVEMBER 2019 -, OGUN

- Member of Google Developer Student Club
- Member of Microsoft Learn Student Ambassadors

Yaba College of Technology / OND Computer Science

MARCH 2017 - DECEMBER 2018, LAGOS

GPA: 3.43

• Member of National Association of Computer Science Students

Hobbies

- Music
- Anime
- Video Games
- Photography